<u>--</u>

Opening statement about me being 10/10 hard-working and motivated. I am currently in my final year of mv undergraduate studies Durham at University, studying Education Studies (English Studies). For my dissertation, I am researching an area of great interest to myself and which I want to research in greater depth at PhD level: the experiences of estranged students UK higher education. particular, I am interested in the ways that estranged students construct their narratives of estrangement, and how these narratives experiences. impact their My own position as an estranged student has greatly influenced this motivation to help other students in my situation to benefit from a higher education in the same way as students with family support, has also provided me with the unique opportunity of working with charities such as Stand Alone to promote awareness of and support for estranged students in HE. Throughout my degree, I have been heavily involved in a range of extra-curricular activities and part-time work. providing me with the time-management skills necessary to undertake PhD study.

Education

2015 — 2018 Durham **Durham University** (St. Aidan's College) BA Education Studies (English Studies)

- Year 2: 70%, 75% in Education
- Year 1: 68%, 71% in Education

Including Modules:

- Higher Education: Issues of Exclusion and Inclusion 74%
- Constructing Childhood and Youth 86%
- Educational Research Methods 68%

Dissertation: Exploring the experiences of estranged students in UK higher education. (Supervised by Dr. Rille Raaper)

Interviews with estranged students at UK universities exploring:

- Issues that they face at university
- What support their university offers them
- How they think support can be improved

2013 — 2015 Spennymoor, Co. Durham

Whitworth Park Sixth Form

A-Level Grades:

- English Literature A*
- History A
- Psychology B
- Extended Project (AS) A*

2008 — 2013 Spennymoor, Co. Durham

Whitworth Park School

GCSE Grades:

- 1 × A^*
 - $-8 \times A$
 - $-2 \times B$
 - $-1 \times C$

Experience Regarding Estrangement

July 2017 Birmingham

Stand Alone and NUS LGBT+

Involved with national Estranged Students' Solidarity Campaign

- Wrote a piece for the campaign's information booklet, distributed to Students Unions nationally
- Attended the launch with Stand Alone at NUS Conference
- Gave a presentation about my experiences as an estranged student at Durham
- Guided Students' Union Officers on how to lobby universities to improve estranged students' experiences

Jul 2017 — Oct 2017 Remote	BBC Three Worked with BBC Three on an article about family estrangement through a series of interviews with a BBC Producer.
Other Experience	
Nov 2017 — Present Durham	Mentor, DU Education Society - Point of contact for a first-year student studying my course - Helping them adapt to university life
Oct 2017 — Present Durham	Hobbies and Games Representative, Durham Students' Union Societies Committee - Lead of Collaboration sub-committee, researching ways to encourage inter-society events - Key point of contact to a range of societies, working to improve their experiences in the union
Jul 2017 — Present Durham	Open Day Ambassador, Durham University - Interacting with prospective students - Assisted in delivering the BA Education Studies presentations
Nov 2016 — Present Durham	Course Representative, Durham University - Reporting the issues faced by students on my course at the Student Staff Consultative Committee

- Elected

Representative

BBC Three

Student

the

on

as

BA Education Studies Programme Committee

Jul 2017

Nov 2016 — Present Nationwide	Games Demonstrator, Esdevium Games - Work at stores/events to demonstrate board games to customers and attendees - Involved in the training of new demonstrators
Mar 2016 — Present Durham	President, Trevelyan College Games Society - Coordinate with Executive Committee - Run frequent events with 30+ students attending
Conference Attended	es and Seminars
Dec 2017	'Who Counts as a Widening Participation Student?' Research Seminar Durham University
Nov 2017 — May 2018	'Institute of Advance Study 'The Future of the University' Public Lecture Series Durham University
Sep 2017	'Student Politics in Contemporary Higher Education — Theory, Policy and Practice' Symposium Durham University
May 2017	'Mind your language: the vocabulary of higher education today' Durham Castle Lecture Durham University
Jul 2016	Teach First Impact Conference Conference Leeds